Curriculum vitae (CV)

Donatas Martinkus

Mobile: +447527337790

Email: donatasmart@gmail.com

About me

I am a software engineer with over 5 years of experience in PHP and MySQL. And 2 years of intense Scala learning curve, applied in building multi micro-service API platform. My personal experiments are mostly developed with latest libs cloned from Git repositories.

I consider myself an efficient worker who always tries to make use of best practices and I like to keep up-to-date with programming theory.

Work experience

11-2014 – Present Position: Software developer

OnTrackRetail Ltd. Type of sector: IT

Type of company: Transportation

Company size: 20-50

Place of work: London, United Kingdom

Scala, Git. Developing multi micro-service based API for various rail companies to unify the unthinkable differences within rail industry.

02-2012 – 10-2014 Position: Software developer

Quidco Type of sector: IT

Type of company: Consumerism Company size: 100-200

Place of work: London, United Kingdom

OOP (PHP), ZF1, Twig, LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, Smarty, jQuery, Git, SVN. Developing vast variety of projects (one project includes icCube third party implementation) to upgrade and support Quidco system.

03-2011 – 02-2012 Position: Senior web developer

Assertis Ltd. Type of sector: IT

Type of company: Transportation

Company size: <10

Place of work: Royal Tunbridge Wells, United Kingdom

OOP (PHP), XSLT, JavaScript, SVN. Working with the xFrame MVC framework, writing unit tests, jQuery and SASS. Applying white labeling to multiple web sites under the same web application.

03-2010 – 03-2011 Position: Web developer

UAB "Group of real estate and

development" (Ltd.)

Type of sector: IT

Type of company: Real Estate

Company size: <10

Place of work: Vilnius, Lithuania

At ReBank I began my knowledge of SVN and Zend Framework. After few months we began to re-develop ReBank system to use Zend Framework and on same side we upgraded DB (it was very unclear and inefficient).

11-2006 – 10-2008 Position: IT specialist **National centre of examination** Type of sector: Education

Type of company: National enterprise

Company size: 20-30

Place of work: Vilnius, Lithuania

Lot's of work with databases (mainly Oracle, a little MySQL). Writing various auto-reports for different exams, also running and configuring other automatic processes.

Education

Academic Specialty: Applied mathematics

09-2003 – 06-2007 Degree: Bachelor **University of Vilnius** Branch: Mathematics

Additional information: I chose stochastic profile in the third term

Technical skills

Languages: Scala, PHP, MySQL, XSLT, JavaScript, CSS, Python (newbie)

Libraries: xFrame, ZF1, jQuery, flot, Twig, Doctrine, Smarty, Twitter Bootstrap, Backbone Tools/Utils: Phing, SASS/LESS, CasperJS, PHPUnit, DBUnit, Selenium, Memcache(d), Gearman

VCS: Git, SVN

Class and certificates

28-01-2008 – 31-01-2008 Organizer: National centre of examination **Scientific results of statistical methods, statistics with SPSS**

Additional information: The seminar topics included: the main statistical problem, the statistical findings of one sample / two samples, the table frequencies, the hypothesis of correlation coefficient equality to zero; non-parametrical criteria; mono-factor, bi-factor and blocked data analysis of variance, cluster analysis, linear, multiple and logistic regression

Hobbies

Judging new / old films, reading science fiction, developing something "awesome", visiting museums, traveling and discovering new lands, collecting heavy music records